Rajavel Pachamuthu

Manager-SDWAN Engineering

• Chennai, India

**** +91-9535323478

☑ raj@rajavel.me

rajavel.me

Summary

Network Engineer with 13 years of experience in designing and deploying Network infrastructure for various Professional services companies and Telecom Service Providers. Proficient in delivering technical support and maintaining enterprise-wide area networks across multi-platform.

Skills

Versa & VeloCloud SD-WAN | AWS and Azure Networking | Cisco Catalyst & Nexus switches, Cisco ISR, ASR & Virtual routers | TCP/IP, BGP, OSPF, EIGRP, vPC, STP, VTP, EtherChannel | Stacking and Layer 2 Security | GRE, IPsec, DMVPN, MPLS, QoS, HSRP, VRRP, NAT | Cisco ISE, Cisco Prime, SolarWinds | Ansible.

Certifications

- CCNP-Enterprise Cisco Certified Network Professional Enterprise.
 - o Specialist: Enterprise Core, Enterprise Design, Enterprise advanced Infrastructure Implementation.
- AWS Certified Advanced Networking Specialty.
- Versa Certified SD-WAN Associate

Work Experience

Tata Communications, Chennai, India

October 2020 - Present

Manager - SDWAN Engineering

- Design and implement Versa SD-WAN solutions for dedicated and multi-tenant deployments.
- Provide technical demonstrations and use cases of the system to customers.
- Validate solution requirements from customers and create SOP documents for support teams.
- Analyze customer solicitations (RFIs, RFPs, etc.), requirements and design solution proposals.

Accenture Solutions Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore, India

July 2013 - October 2020

Network Specialist

- Installed & supported network infrastructure of a Danish Manufacturing company of 200+ locations.
- Migrated 200+ branch locations from traditional MPLS and DMVPN to VeloCloud SDWAN.
- Designed Cloud readiness project and enabled Network connectivity to Azure from Hubs and branches.

Sify Technologies Ltd, Chennai, India

November 2011 - July 2013

Global NOC Engineer

- Provisioned and supported MPLS VPN and Internet WAN circuits for customers.
- Integrated 100+ member bank branches under state owned IDRBT MPLS VPN network.
- Provided technical solutions and implemented new requirements for Managed Customers.

Firstsource Solutions, Chennai, India

September 2010 - November 2011

Junior NOC Engineer

• Provided L1 support for IPLC, MPLS and Internet circuits of 30+ locations and worked with service providers to diagnose and fix network issues.

Allnet Systems Pvt. Ltd., Chennai, India

July 2009 - September 2010

Network Engineer

• Configured and managed 10+ customer networks which includes servers, network and VoIP devices.

Education

Anna University, Chennai, India Bachelor of Engineering (Electronics & Communication Engineering) April 2009